<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!-- generator="wordpress/2.0.1" -->
<rss version="2.0" 
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
<channel>
	<title>Comments on: Should Database Manage The Meaning?</title>
	<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/09/29/should-database-manage-the-meaning/</link>
	<description>AAaaaaahhhhrrrrrrr!</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2007 09:11:38 +0000</pubDate>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=2.0.1</generator>

	<item>
		<title>by: Balance On Rails : David Hansson e Opinionated Software</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/09/29/should-database-manage-the-meaning/#comment-19887</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2006 15:55:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/09/29/should-database-manage-the-meaning/#comment-19887</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;[...] Atualização: Alex Bunardzic tem uma excelente sequência entitulada Devem os Bancos de Dados Gerenciar o Significado? &amp;#8211; fique ligado. [...]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[&#8230;] Atualização: Alex Bunardzic tem uma excelente sequência entitulada Devem os Bancos de Dados Gerenciar o Significado? &#8211; fique ligado. [&#8230;]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Madeblog &#187; ActiveRecord Angst&#8230; ReActivated.</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/09/29/should-database-manage-the-meaning/#comment-18380</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2006 16:05:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/09/29/should-database-manage-the-meaning/#comment-18380</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;[...] It&amp;#8217;s LAMP right? Not LAPP, LAOP, LASSP or LADP. Despite the accusations regularly levelled at MySQL, I think that&amp;#8217;s what most of us use and if you believe in getting everything through your ORM then there&amp;#8217;s a good argument that you really want your database to play dumb. [...]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[&#8230;] It&#8217;s LAMP right? Not LAPP, LAOP, LASSP or LADP. Despite the accusations regularly levelled at MySQL, I think that&#8217;s what most of us use and if you believe in getting everything through your ORM then there&#8217;s a good argument that you really want your database to play dumb. [&#8230;]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Madeblog &#187; Blog Archive &#187; ActiveRecord Angst&#8230; ReActivated.</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/09/29/should-database-manage-the-meaning/#comment-1140</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2006 16:52:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/09/29/should-database-manage-the-meaning/#comment-1140</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;[...] It&amp;#8217;s LAMP right? Not LAPP, LAOP, LASSP or LADP. Despite the accusations regularly levelled at MySQL, I think that&amp;#8217;s what most of us use and if you believe in getting everything through your ORM then there&amp;#8217;s a good argument that you really want your database to play dumb. [...]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[&#8230;] It&#8217;s LAMP right? Not LAPP, LAOP, LASSP or LADP. Despite the accusations regularly levelled at MySQL, I think that&#8217;s what most of us use and if you believe in getting everything through your ORM then there&#8217;s a good argument that you really want your database to play dumb. [&#8230;]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Shawn Oster</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/09/29/should-database-manage-the-meaning/#comment-1134</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2006 23:54:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/09/29/should-database-manage-the-meaning/#comment-1134</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;I watch this debate ping-pong back and forth across time but one thing I don't see a lot of is Real World situations.  I've worked with a lot of different databases and more often I've found contraints limiting rather than helpful, &lt;em&gt;especially&lt;/em&gt; when dealing with multiple apps written in multiple languages accessing the same DB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've seen address tables locked down because a bad schema design required a relationship to an account table.  A duplicate table had to be created for non-account addresses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I watched a 5 minute &quot;I'll just change that in the DB&quot; turn into a 2 hour frustration session by the DB due to the mountain of RI constraints.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've spent hours trying to track down unclear error messages when I tried to delete a record from a table that had a RI because the DB abstraction layer I was using didn't understand a new error code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've been stuck twiddling my thumbs because the DBA was on vacation or was out sick that week and I needed a change made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've gone drinking because I found out that there was no source control on a database's stored procs and it was either drink or stab someone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've watched programs do &lt;em&gt;no validation&lt;/em&gt; in their apps or pages because they assumed the database was going to catch any errors.  You know, because the DBA said so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In many years and many companies of many sizes I've rarely if ever seen apps that were &lt;em&gt;less&lt;/em&gt; stable when backed into databases that lacked RI.  I can't ever remember a time I spent hours tracking down a bug due to invalid data in the database but I've wasted days and weeks trying to work around constraints.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Milage varies but that's what I've seen.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I watch this debate ping-pong back and forth across time but one thing I don&#8217;t see a lot of is Real World situations.  I&#8217;ve worked with a lot of different databases and more often I&#8217;ve found contraints limiting rather than helpful, <em>especially</em> when dealing with multiple apps written in multiple languages accessing the same DB.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve seen address tables locked down because a bad schema design required a relationship to an account table.  A duplicate table had to be created for non-account addresses.</p>
<p>I watched a 5 minute &#8220;I&#8217;ll just change that in the DB&#8221; turn into a 2 hour frustration session by the DB due to the mountain of RI constraints.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve spent hours trying to track down unclear error messages when I tried to delete a record from a table that had a RI because the DB abstraction layer I was using didn&#8217;t understand a new error code.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve been stuck twiddling my thumbs because the DBA was on vacation or was out sick that week and I needed a change made.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve gone drinking because I found out that there was no source control on a database&#8217;s stored procs and it was either drink or stab someone.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve watched programs do <em>no validation</em> in their apps or pages because they assumed the database was going to catch any errors.  You know, because the DBA said so.</p>
<p>In many years and many companies of many sizes I&#8217;ve rarely if ever seen apps that were <em>less</em> stable when backed into databases that lacked RI.  I can&#8217;t ever remember a time I spent hours tracking down a bug due to invalid data in the database but I&#8217;ve wasted days and weeks trying to work around constraints.</p>
<p>Milage varies but that&#8217;s what I&#8217;ve seen.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Martin</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/09/29/should-database-manage-the-meaning/#comment-920</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2006 16:44:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/09/29/should-database-manage-the-meaning/#comment-920</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;You are all talking about different apps hitting on your database, and that being the only problem with &quot;application databases&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, what if you do load-balancing, and have several apps of the &lt;em&gt;same kind&lt;/em&gt; hitting your database at the same time?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;you'll need some central integrity checking in your database then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;regards,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Martin&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>You are all talking about different apps hitting on your database, and that being the only problem with &#8220;application databases&#8221;.</p>
<p>Now, what if you do load-balancing, and have several apps of the <em>same kind</em> hitting your database at the same time?</p>
<p>you&#8217;ll need some central integrity checking in your database then.</p>
<p>regards,</p>
<p>Martin</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Anonymous</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/09/29/should-database-manage-the-meaning/#comment-831</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2005 19:58:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/09/29/should-database-manage-the-meaning/#comment-831</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;&quot;Managing the meaning of the data&quot; is a just a straw man! The developmer manages the meaning of the data by specifying constraints and FKs, the database simply ENFORCES those rules.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;Managing the meaning of the data&#8221; is a just a straw man! The developmer manages the meaning of the data by specifying constraints and FKs, the database simply ENFORCES those rules.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Bob B</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/09/29/should-database-manage-the-meaning/#comment-747</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2005 18:48:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/09/29/should-database-manage-the-meaning/#comment-747</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Let's compare databases to word processors the &lt;em&gt;right&lt;/em&gt; way.  Database constraints map nicely to word processor formatting.  I can tell the word processor to use double spacing, to use the arial font, to use 14 pt, to underline something, etc etc.  I can apply it to as little or as much of the meaningful data as I want and the word processor makes sure those rules apply.      The same is true of database constraints.  This column is not null, that one is a number, this one must exist in that table.column.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I establish the rules of my data formatting and the database or word processor ensures that all data conforms to those rules.  The database is just an application at heart, one which is built to store, retrieve, recover, constrain, and manage gobs of data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a side note, there is one huge advantage to a well-designed database.  It can change its access path based on the amount and type of data put into it.    It can switch between brute force (full table scan), indexed access (unique location and index scanning), and hashing.  Furthermore, the databases are created by tons of talented developers with a huge base of users testing.  Not only are the database owners testing it, but so are the database users.  There are few applications that can say they have had that many users test their system - EVER.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Databases are not bit boxes.  While they do seem to serve that purpose, they are much more complex on the inside than is outwardly noticeable.  If developers do not understand what it is doing, why it is doing it, and how to take advantage of it, I would not want them to implement data management in &lt;em&gt;my&lt;/em&gt; applications.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Let&#8217;s compare databases to word processors the <em>right</em> way.  Database constraints map nicely to word processor formatting.  I can tell the word processor to use double spacing, to use the arial font, to use 14 pt, to underline something, etc etc.  I can apply it to as little or as much of the meaningful data as I want and the word processor makes sure those rules apply.      The same is true of database constraints.  This column is not null, that one is a number, this one must exist in that table.column.  </p>
<p>I establish the rules of my data formatting and the database or word processor ensures that all data conforms to those rules.  The database is just an application at heart, one which is built to store, retrieve, recover, constrain, and manage gobs of data.</p>
<p>On a side note, there is one huge advantage to a well-designed database.  It can change its access path based on the amount and type of data put into it.    It can switch between brute force (full table scan), indexed access (unique location and index scanning), and hashing.  Furthermore, the databases are created by tons of talented developers with a huge base of users testing.  Not only are the database owners testing it, but so are the database users.  There are few applications that can say they have had that many users test their system - EVER.</p>
<p>Databases are not bit boxes.  While they do seem to serve that purpose, they are much more complex on the inside than is outwardly noticeable.  If developers do not understand what it is doing, why it is doing it, and how to take advantage of it, I would not want them to implement data management in <em>my</em> applications.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Ethical Software by Alex Bunardzic &#187; Confessions Of A Former Data Integrity Addict</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/09/29/should-database-manage-the-meaning/#comment-738</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2005 20:18:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/09/29/should-database-manage-the-meaning/#comment-738</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;[...] But the confusion crept in regarding the boundaries of the applicability of this theory. I wrote about these boundaries in several previous articles (Should Database Manage The Meaning?, Shared Data and Mobile Data, and so on). Needless to say, such soul-searching writings provoked an avalanche of emotional outburst from the database crowd. [...]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[&#8230;] But the confusion crept in regarding the boundaries of the applicability of this theory. I wrote about these boundaries in several previous articles (Should Database Manage The Meaning?, Shared Data and Mobile Data, and so on). Needless to say, such soul-searching writings provoked an avalanche of emotional outburst from the database crowd. [&#8230;]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: wjv</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/09/29/should-database-manage-the-meaning/#comment-714</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2005 08:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/09/29/should-database-manage-the-meaning/#comment-714</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Oh, lookee, this post made Fabian Pascal's &quot;to laugh or cry&quot; links.  And to think that the smart money was on the original DHH post to be quoted there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frankly, I've settled for laughing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Oh, lookee, this post made Fabian Pascal&#8217;s &#8220;to laugh or cry&#8221; links.  And to think that the smart money was on the original DHH post to be quoted there.</p>
<p>Frankly, I&#8217;ve settled for laughing.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Ethical Software by Alex Bunardzic &#187; The Myth Of Data Integrity</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/09/29/should-database-manage-the-meaning/#comment-713</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2005 04:09:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/09/29/should-database-manage-the-meaning/#comment-713</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;[...] David is, of course, right. I don&amp;#8217;t have to go any further than point out the reaction to my posts on the same subject, of which the most notoriously acute was Should Database Manage The Meaning? As one of the programmers (Valentino Volonghi) who indulged in the ensuing discussion had pointed out, &amp;#8220;This is totally nonsense to me.&amp;#8221; [...]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[&#8230;] David is, of course, right. I don&#8217;t have to go any further than point out the reaction to my posts on the same subject, of which the most notoriously acute was Should Database Manage The Meaning? As one of the programmers (Valentino Volonghi) who indulged in the ensuing discussion had pointed out, &#8220;This is totally nonsense to me.&#8221; [&#8230;]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
</channel>
</rss>

<!-- Dynamic Page Served (once) in 0.352 seconds -->
<!-- Cached page served by WP-Cache -->
