<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!-- generator="wordpress/2.0.1" -->
<rss version="2.0" 
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
<channel>
	<title>Comments on: Hello, my name is Ryan Tomayko&#8230;</title>
	<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/06/30/hello/</link>
	<description>AAaaaaahhhhrrrrrrr!</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2007 09:12:11 +0000</pubDate>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=2.0.1</generator>

	<item>
		<title>by: Andy Elvey</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/06/30/hello/#comment-25</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2005 07:41:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/06/30/hello/#comment-25</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Hi Ryan!  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just thought I'd drop you a line to say &quot;nice site&quot; (and I very much support the &quot;less is more&quot; approach with software).  Most of all, I strongly agree that web development is a mess!  Javascript (in particular),  HTML - the lot. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might be interested in a language on S/F called &lt;a href=&quot;http://sourceforge.net/projects/r-sharp&quot;&gt;r-sharp&lt;/a&gt;  .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the name, it has nothing to do with MS and C# - it is actually an open-source clone of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rebol.com&quot;&gt;Rebol&lt;/a&gt;.  The project seems dead now, but I really recommend having a look. There is code released and it works!  I've tried it.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is another Rebol clone here - &lt;a href=&quot;http://sourceforge.net/projects/freebell&quot;&gt;freebell&lt;/a&gt;. Freebell is written in Java.  Although it says &quot;no code has been released&quot; , there is code (and lots of it) in the CVS there.  It seems to be quite complete, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rebol itself is free but (unfortunately) not open-source.  R-sharp and Freebell are both. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rebol is amazing - a full GUI environment, a flexible and ultra-succinct syntax - all in less than 500 Kb or so.  It is ultra-lightweight, supports all net protocols, and the demos show that it is possible to do some amazing stuff - graphics and lots more. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway - although I'm not brilliant on the coding myself, I try to mention r-sharp and freebell when I can - they are a couple of gems just waiting to be discovered :-)  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bye for now!  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Andy&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi Ryan!  </p>
<p>Just thought I&#8217;d drop you a line to say &#8220;nice site&#8221; (and I very much support the &#8220;less is more&#8221; approach with software).  Most of all, I strongly agree that web development is a mess!  Javascript (in particular),  HTML - the lot. </p>
<p>You might be interested in a language on S/F called <a href="http://sourceforge.net/projects/r-sharp">r-sharp</a>  .</p>
<p>Despite the name, it has nothing to do with MS and C# - it is actually an open-source clone of <a href="http://www.rebol.com">Rebol</a>.  The project seems dead now, but I really recommend having a look. There is code released and it works!  I&#8217;ve tried it.  </p>
<p>There is another Rebol clone here - <a href="http://sourceforge.net/projects/freebell">freebell</a>. Freebell is written in Java.  Although it says &#8220;no code has been released&#8221; , there is code (and lots of it) in the CVS there.  It seems to be quite complete, too.</p>
<p>Rebol itself is free but (unfortunately) not open-source.  R-sharp and Freebell are both. </p>
<p>Rebol is amazing - a full GUI environment, a flexible and ultra-succinct syntax - all in less than 500 Kb or so.  It is ultra-lightweight, supports all net protocols, and the demos show that it is possible to do some amazing stuff - graphics and lots more. </p>
<p>Anyway - although I&#8217;m not brilliant on the coding myself, I try to mention r-sharp and freebell when I can - they are a couple of gems just waiting to be discovered :-)  </p>
<p>Bye for now!  </p>
<p>Andy</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
</channel>
</rss>

<!-- Dynamic Page Served (once) in 0.282 seconds -->
<!-- Cached page served by WP-Cache -->
