<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
      xml:lang="en"
      >
    <title>lesscode.org</title>
    <subtitle>AAaaaaahhhhrrrrrrr!</subtitle>
    <id>http://lesscode.org/</id>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://lesscode.org/feed/atom/"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://lesscode.org/"/>
    <updated>2007-08-19T14:16:25Z</updated>
    <rights>Copyright 2006</rights>
    <generator uri="http://wordpress.org/" version="2.0.1">WordPress</generator>
        <entry>
        <author>
            <name>Ryan Tomayko</name>
        </author>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ Magpie&#8217;s Django / Rails comparison ]]></title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://lesscode.org/2005/08/16/magpies-django-rails-comparison/"/>
        <id>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/16/magpies-django-rails-comparison/</id>
        <published>2005-08-16T16:14:29Z</published>
        <updated>2005-08-16T16:14:29Z</updated>
        <category scheme="http://lesscode.org/category/"
                  term="rails-vs-django/"
                  label="Rails v. Django"/>
        <summary type="html">
            <![CDATA[ Sam Newman has a nice comparison on Django and Rails. ]]>
        </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[ <p>Sam Newman has a <a href="http://www.magpiebrain.com/archives/2005/08/14/rails_and_django" title="A comparison of Django with Rails">fairly thorough comparison</a> of <a href="http://www.djangoproject.com/" title="Django - The web framework for perfectionists with deadlines">Django</a> and
<a href="http://www.rubyonrails.com/" title="Ruby on Rails">Rails</a> over at magpiebrain.com. He compares the following traits of
the frameworks: language, requirements and installation, deployment
options, caching, project setup, adding models, interaction with the
database, projects and applications, controllers and URLs, templating
options, and administration / user management. </p>

<p>It&#8217;s a nice comparison, although the concluding section on choosing a
framework seems to be getting some flak:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>If you are developing a simple (in a domain model sense) application
  where you want to use Ajax to deliver a great UI, Rails is probably
  for you. If however you want to develop an entire site with different
  types of applications within it - then Django’s plugable applications
  and general approach might be what you’re after. Equally, the better
  user and administration side of Django favours portal style
  applications – this is something you’ll have to do yourself if you
  want to use Rails.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Rails is, of course, not limited to AJAX-heavy apps with simple domain
models. I&#8217;m assuming Sam didn&#8217;t mean to give that impression but was
just trying to wrap up a long article quickly. Perhaps he&#8217;ll clarify a
bit.</p>

<p>Django committer, Jacob Kaplan-Moss, followed up with <a href="http://www.jacobian.org/2005/aug/16/django_and_rails/">some thoughts on
the post</a>.</p>

<p>As a side note, I <a href="http://lesscode.org/2005/07/17/rails-django-compared/" title="Rails and Django Compared">had planned to do a series around this</a> but I
promised <a href="http://www.holovaty.com/">Adrian</a> and Jacob I&#8217;d hold off until
Django was <em>launched-launched</em>, which I assumed meant 1.0 at the time
but that seems a ways off now&#8230; I&#8217;m not sure Django can get any more
launched at this point so I might have to revisit that promise as I&#8217;m
anxious to get moving on this.</p>
 ]]>
        </content>
                    </entry>
    <entry>
        <author>
            <name>Ryan Tomayko</name>
        </author>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ Rails and Django Compared ]]></title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://lesscode.org/2005/07/17/rails-django-compared/"/>
        <id>http://lesscode.org/2005/07/17/rails-django-compared/</id>
        <published>2005-07-17T19:48:24Z</published>
        <updated>2006-10-29T21:31:02Z</updated>
        <category scheme="http://lesscode.org/category/"
                  term="by-status/then-they-laugh-at-you/"
                  label="Then they laugh at you..."/>
        <category scheme="http://lesscode.org/category/"
                  term="rails-vs-django/"
                  label="Rails v. Django"/>
        <summary type="html">
            <![CDATA[ I plan on diving deep into the two frameworks so instead of one large post, I'm going to make this a running series. ]]>
        </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[ <p>Once <a href="http://djangoproject.org/" title="Django">Django</a> is <em>launched-launched</em>, I&#8217;ll be comparing various
aspects of it with <a href="http://www.rubyonrails.com/" title="Ruby on Rails">Ruby on Rails</a>. I plan on diving deep into
the two frameworks so instead of one large post, I&#8217;m going to make this
a running series.</p>

<p>While I&#8217;m primarily a Python coder, I&#8217;ve been dabbling with Ruby for
about a year and have a couple of apps under my belt with Rails. They
are admittedly simple apps but what isn&#8217;t with Rails? I&#8217;ve also logged
70-80 hours against a Python clone of Rails&#8217; excellent implementation of
Active Record, which put me pretty deep into the internals of that
piece.</p>

<p>I am not a Python zealot. And, to be honest, I&#8217;m floating between the
two languages as my primary. What I&#8217;m trying to say is that my interest
is in exploring these two frameworks objectively and extending my
understanding of each, not advocating one over the other. I will include
personal thoughts on design and may favor one or the other at this level
but I will not be concluding the series with a recommendation for either
because, frankly, I already know which I&#8217;d recommend at present and it
has nothing to do with technical qualities (hint: <a href="http://www.loudthinking.com/arc/000484.html" title="Growing an open source ecosystem">it has everything to
do with this</a>).</p>

<p>That being said, I <em>can</em> recommend that if you are building systems that
require the complexity of a full-stack web framework (i.e. <a href="http://www.megginson.com/blogs/quoderat/archives/2005/06/11/rails-vs-php-mvc-or-view-centric/" title="Rails vs. PHP: MVC or view-centric">PHP, CGI
won&#8217;t cut it</a>) and you are currently using something other than one
of these two frameworks in any language (including Java and .NET) on any
platform, that you move swiftly to adopt either if possible. If there is
something barring you from making that switch, well, <a href="http://intertwingly.net/slides/2005/rs/7.html" title="Where's your patch?">where&#8217;s your
patch?</a> Make it happen.</p>

<p>I realize that many in the Python community have already grown
comfortable with an existing framework (or more likely, have written
their own, like myself) and that&#8217;s fine as there are some competent
frameworks out there. But it has become apparent that Django will be
growing a large community of contributors and that&#8217;s something no
current Python web framework of this kind can boast.</p>

<p>As I write this, there are 30 people idling in #django on
irc.freenode.net on a Sunday morning, two days after the none-launch;
there&#8217;s been <a href="http://del.icio.us/url/980ce09131008f964385d9fc6bf5c319">409 bookmarks on del.icio.us</a>.
Granted this is all very much driven by hype right now as there hasn&#8217;t
been any real experience with the framework, <a href="http://simon.incutio.com/archive/2005/07/17/django">excepting the
maintainers</a>, but
the outlook for a large community to finally coalesce around a single
set of tools and conventions is promising.</p>

<p>I also want to mention that I spent some time talking to the Django
maintainers last night and they&#8217;ve convinced me that the Rails
comparisons, while unavoidable, may be somewhat premature. Although
Django has many of the same traits as Rails, it wasn&#8217;t built as an all
out clone and may appeal to a slightly different set of
requirements. Time will tell, of course, but as of right now the
similarities are a huge part of what&#8217;s driving interest in Django and
there&#8217;s a good reason for that - Rails got a ton right.</p>

<p>Still, &#8220;because it&#8217;s in Rails&#8221; is unlikely to be considered sufficient
justification for Django feature requests. That&#8217;s a sure way of creating
a <em>Bride of Frankenstein</em> framework and I&#8217;m pleased to see the
maintainers have a strong sense of this. Django is likely to follow many
of the same paths as Rails but that&#8217;s because they were both designed
under real life circumstances with similarly excellent philosophy.</p>

<p>Before I wrap this up, I&#8217;d like to echo the sentiments of <a href="http://blog.yanime.org/articles/2005/07/16/ruby-has-rails-python-now-has-django">one Rails
supporter</a> 
in his comments on Django:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I hope Rails learns to play with Django and they&#8217;ll not smite each
  other (if not friends, don&#8217;t be enemies). The world is big enough. A
  combined message from different camps will be more resounding than any
  one camp trying to say he is the bestest - and coming off as naive or
  clueless.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Indeed.</p>

<p>(<em>warning:</em> stomach wrenching, <em>KUM BAI AH</em>, everyone-hold-hands type
stuff imminent)</p>

<p>The Ruby, Python, Perl, and PHP communities must understand the immense
opportunities that await them should they accept that they share much
more in common than not and that a unified front would go a long way in
tearing down the barriers that have kept these technologies out of the
mainstream. The amount of positive impact these disruptive technologies
could have on existing forms of business and social interaction in
general are limited only by our ability to tell the story.</p>

<p>Feeds for the series:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://lesscode.org/category/rails-vs-django/feed/">RSS2</a></li>
<li><a href="http://lesscode.org/category/rails-vs-django/feed/atom/">Atom 0.3</a></li>
</ul>
 ]]>
        </content>
                    </entry>
</feed>

<!-- Dynamic Page Served (once) in 0.336 seconds -->
