<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!-- generator="wordpress/2.0.1" -->
<rss version="2.0" 
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
<channel>
	<title>Comments on: Rails Furthers Industry Acceptance</title>
	<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/07/15/more-j2ee-vs-rails/</link>
	<description>AAaaaaahhhhrrrrrrr!</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2007 09:13:10 +0000</pubDate>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=2.0.1</generator>

	<item>
		<title>by: Candide</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/07/15/more-j2ee-vs-rails/#comment-7728</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2006 22:02:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/07/15/more-j2ee-vs-rails/#comment-7728</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Of course, the bane of less code is that you have no clue what's going on when push comes to shove.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm running into this problem right now with adding a column to a development project I'm working on: I've updated my database, added a new column, re-created the scaffolding through the generator, and...nothing.  Nix.  Nada.  That column (book_id) simply refused to show up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer?  Change the name of the column.  For some reason, the scaffolding REALLY did not care for the &quot;book_id&quot; column.  I'd like to know where that is in the documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Of course, the bane of less code is that you have no clue what&#8217;s going on when push comes to shove.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m running into this problem right now with adding a column to a development project I&#8217;m working on: I&#8217;ve updated my database, added a new column, re-created the scaffolding through the generator, and&#8230;nothing.  Nix.  Nada.  That column (book_id) simply refused to show up.</p>
<p>The answer?  Change the name of the column.  For some reason, the scaffolding REALLY did not care for the &#8220;book_id&#8221; column.  I&#8217;d like to know where that is in the documentation.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Freedom vs. Safety [@lesscode.org]</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/07/15/more-j2ee-vs-rails/#comment-286</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2005 18:44:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/07/15/more-j2ee-vs-rails/#comment-286</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;[...] The advocates of freedom languages tend to talk first about the speed and efficiency of the individual programmer. They discuss the expressive power of different constructs and focus on all the powerful features that the safety languages lack. They point out complex patterns and show off twenty-line systems that do the same thing. They talk more about the ease or purity of things than the safety of things. They are dismissive of static-type-safety and compile-time validation in general. [...]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[&#8230;] The advocates of freedom languages tend to talk first about the speed and efficiency of the individual programmer. They discuss the expressive power of different constructs and focus on all the powerful features that the safety languages lack. They point out complex patterns and show off twenty-line systems that do the same thing. They talk more about the ease or purity of things than the safety of things. They are dismissive of static-type-safety and compile-time validation in general. [&#8230;]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: blogx &#187; Blog Archive &#187; LISP</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/07/15/more-j2ee-vs-rails/#comment-198</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2005 22:44:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/07/15/more-j2ee-vs-rails/#comment-198</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;[...] Interesting reading this morning about a language that was written in 1958 called LISP, and is the powerhouse behind all those airline search engines out there. Got there from a mention on the list about Ruby on Rails that led me to one of Ryan Tomayko&amp;#8217;s articles about less code. The song remains the same. [...]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[&#8230;] Interesting reading this morning about a language that was written in 1958 called LISP, and is the powerhouse behind all those airline search engines out there. Got there from a mention on the list about Ruby on Rails that led me to one of Ryan Tomayko&#8217;s articles about less code. The song remains the same. [&#8230;]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Ryan Tomayko</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/07/15/more-j2ee-vs-rails/#comment-92</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2005 14:55:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/07/15/more-j2ee-vs-rails/#comment-92</guid>
					<description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;So what is it exactly that you are doing about having “a hard time reporting on all the recent Rails press”?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ahh, well, I've been conversing with a few really solid Ruby and Rails developers trying to get them to come on board with lesscode.org. That way I don't have to worry about being fair and balanced because there will be someone concentrating on covering the Ruby community. In fact, I've spoken to people from the Perl, Python, PHP, and Ruby communities as well as some general web architecture guys that understand why these tools were built the way they were.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The interest seems to be there but everyone has two or three weblogs + columns at this point. I've not given up hope completely, we'll just have to wait and see.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>So what is it exactly that you are doing about having “a hard time reporting on all the recent Rails press”?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Ahh, well, I&#8217;ve been conversing with a few really solid Ruby and Rails developers trying to get them to come on board with lesscode.org. That way I don&#8217;t have to worry about being fair and balanced because there will be someone concentrating on covering the Ruby community. In fact, I&#8217;ve spoken to people from the Perl, Python, PHP, and Ruby communities as well as some general web architecture guys that understand why these tools were built the way they were.</p>
<p>The interest seems to be there but everyone has two or three weblogs + columns at this point. I&#8217;ve not given up hope completely, we&#8217;ll just have to wait and see.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: John Speno</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/07/15/more-j2ee-vs-rails/#comment-91</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2005 14:06:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/07/15/more-j2ee-vs-rails/#comment-91</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;So what is it exactly that you are doing about having &quot;a hard time reporting on all the recent Rails press&quot;?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So what is it exactly that you are doing about having &#8220;a hard time reporting on all the recent Rails press&#8221;?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Dannno</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/07/15/more-j2ee-vs-rails/#comment-56</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2005 13:15:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/07/15/more-j2ee-vs-rails/#comment-56</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Waxy posted a link to Django &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.djangoproject.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Django&lt;/a&gt; yesteday which purports to be Rails for Python, though, being unfamiliar with Python, I was unable to assess the claim (No offense Pythoners, I just don't jive with the syntax, like I don't jive with Lisp's syntax).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Waxy posted a link to Django <a href="http://www.djangoproject.com/">Django</a> yesteday which purports to be Rails for Python, though, being unfamiliar with Python, I was unable to assess the claim (No offense Pythoners, I just don&#8217;t jive with the syntax, like I don&#8217;t jive with Lisp&#8217;s syntax).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: PJ Hyett</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/07/15/more-j2ee-vs-rails/#comment-54</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2005 01:31:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/07/15/more-j2ee-vs-rails/#comment-54</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;That article (and specifically the code example you've posted) was one of those beautiful occasions when it becomes perfectly clear that the Java folks that continually put down Rails need to eat crow. The KISS method comes to mind.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>That article (and specifically the code example you&#8217;ve posted) was one of those beautiful occasions when it becomes perfectly clear that the Java folks that continually put down Rails need to eat crow. The KISS method comes to mind.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Jordan Cox</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/07/15/more-j2ee-vs-rails/#comment-53</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2005 20:09:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/07/15/more-j2ee-vs-rails/#comment-53</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;I always try to learn as many languages as possible.  For me, Ruby on Rails was a great chance to dive into Ruby - and I'm glad I did.  It's a very robust language, that's still very simple - and has finally gotten this gr(e&amp;#124;a)y procedural programmer to fully embrace OO.  :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seconds on the great blog comment.  I love it.  The design is wonderfully different - and I love the concept.  Keep it up!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I always try to learn as many languages as possible.  For me, Ruby on Rails was a great chance to dive into Ruby - and I&#8217;m glad I did.  It&#8217;s a very robust language, that&#8217;s still very simple - and has finally gotten this gr(e|a)y procedural programmer to fully embrace OO.  :)</p>
<p>Seconds on the great blog comment.  I love it.  The design is wonderfully different - and I love the concept.  Keep it up!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: ludo</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/07/15/more-j2ee-vs-rails/#comment-44</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2005 10:04:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/07/15/more-j2ee-vs-rails/#comment-44</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;I think may Python lovers are in my same situation, having postponed  learning Ruby for a while in the hope that a Rails-like framework for Python would eventually get developed. Unfortunately it looks like we will have to learn Ruby, or find the time to develop PyRails (which will involve learning Ruby anyway).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BTW, great blog!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I think may Python lovers are in my same situation, having postponed  learning Ruby for a while in the hope that a Rails-like framework for Python would eventually get developed. Unfortunately it looks like we will have to learn Ruby, or find the time to develop PyRails (which will involve learning Ruby anyway).</p>
<p>BTW, great blog!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
</channel>
</rss>

<!-- Dynamic Page Served (once) in 0.389 seconds -->
<!-- Cached page served by WP-Cache -->
