<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!-- generator="wordpress/2.0.1" -->
<rss version="2.0" 
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
<channel>
	<title>Comments on: Looking for Contributors</title>
	<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/09/looking-for-contributors/</link>
	<description>AAaaaaahhhhrrrrrrr!</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2007 09:12:49 +0000</pubDate>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=2.0.1</generator>

	<item>
		<title>by: Ryan Tomayko</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/09/looking-for-contributors/#comment-197</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2005 04:34:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/09/looking-for-contributors/#comment-197</guid>
					<description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;One would have thought that “drop names” indicates names other than one’s one. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No, that's fine. I could have sworn I had a little blurb about recommending yourself being okay in the post. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've already received a good amount of requests. I'm going to take on a few, see what happens, and then open it up again. Please keep the recommendations coming though. I might have to backlog some of these at some point but I'll definitely get in touch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks everyone!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>One would have thought that “drop names” indicates names other than one’s one. :)</p>
</blockquote>
<p>No, that&#8217;s fine. I could have sworn I had a little blurb about recommending yourself being okay in the post. </p>
<p>I&#8217;ve already received a good amount of requests. I&#8217;m going to take on a few, see what happens, and then open it up again. Please keep the recommendations coming though. I might have to backlog some of these at some point but I&#8217;ll definitely get in touch.</p>
<p>Thanks everyone!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Alex</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/09/looking-for-contributors/#comment-196</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2005 03:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/09/looking-for-contributors/#comment-196</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Heh, you are of course right, but the meglomaniac half of me wishes to disagree. :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Heh, you are of course right, but the meglomaniac half of me wishes to disagree. :)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Anonymous</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/09/looking-for-contributors/#comment-195</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2005 01:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/09/looking-for-contributors/#comment-195</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;One would have thought that &quot;drop names&quot; indicates names other than one's one. :D&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One would have thought that &#8220;drop names&#8221; indicates names other than one&#8217;s one. :D</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Alex</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/09/looking-for-contributors/#comment-194</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2005 23:56:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/09/looking-for-contributors/#comment-194</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Hi there. I'm always interested in pushing my opinion on the minions out there, but then again, my incredible intellect warns me that perhaps it's best to keep it to myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;ahem&lt;/em&gt; Let's start over. I'm a freak of all things markup and semantic, especially Topic Maps and variations thereof. I have a fetish for things new and shiny, balanced with a love-affair with XSLT and PHP. Yeah, a freak. Like I said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi there. I&#8217;m always interested in pushing my opinion on the minions out there, but then again, my incredible intellect warns me that perhaps it&#8217;s best to keep it to myself.</p>
<p><em>ahem</em> Let&#8217;s start over. I&#8217;m a freak of all things markup and semantic, especially Topic Maps and variations thereof. I have a fetish for things new and shiny, balanced with a love-affair with XSLT and PHP. Yeah, a freak. Like I said.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Alex Bunardzic</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/09/looking-for-contributors/#comment-193</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2005 23:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/09/looking-for-contributors/#comment-193</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Hi Ryan,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been inspired in the past year or so to start my own soapbox on the web, and was working toward it, until the day when I stumbled upon this community. I think what you guys are doing here is incredibly encouraging, and I would really feel honored if you would include me into the fold, and allow me to be the contributor to this awesome meeting place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My background: five years in scientific research (started in 1985 on complex systems modeling), followed by 15 years of software development. I've been through it all -- FORTRAN, Pascal, C, Smalltalk, C++, VB, Java, ERP, J2EE, EAI, SOA, .NET, and finally (thankfully:-) Ruby and Rails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me, software development is at its very core a social skill. The reason it's in such a mess right now is because the majority of developers have fairly rudimentary social skills to begin with. That needs to change if we are to see any overall improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am hoping that you will offer me a chance to post one trial article, to see how it goes. I am very passionate about software, and would hate to see all these efforts dilluted and fragmented, or wasted on places such at the Serverside etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best regards,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alex&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi Ryan,</p>
<p>I have been inspired in the past year or so to start my own soapbox on the web, and was working toward it, until the day when I stumbled upon this community. I think what you guys are doing here is incredibly encouraging, and I would really feel honored if you would include me into the fold, and allow me to be the contributor to this awesome meeting place.</p>
<p>My background: five years in scientific research (started in 1985 on complex systems modeling), followed by 15 years of software development. I&#8217;ve been through it all &#8212; FORTRAN, Pascal, C, Smalltalk, C++, VB, Java, ERP, J2EE, EAI, SOA, .NET, and finally (thankfully:-) Ruby and Rails.</p>
<p>To me, software development is at its very core a social skill. The reason it&#8217;s in such a mess right now is because the majority of developers have fairly rudimentary social skills to begin with. That needs to change if we are to see any overall improvement.</p>
<p>I am hoping that you will offer me a chance to post one trial article, to see how it goes. I am very passionate about software, and would hate to see all these efforts dilluted and fragmented, or wasted on places such at the Serverside etc.</p>
<p>Best regards,</p>
<p>Alex</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Richard Dyce</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/09/looking-for-contributors/#comment-192</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2005 11:41:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/09/looking-for-contributors/#comment-192</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Hi, not sure if you're in the market for a hasbeen Brit? I've been reading your stuff for a few weeks now, and nodding my head in agreement/laughing my coffee up the wall at inappropriate places - and I think you have caught the zeitgeist - for css, ror, ajax etc. I might have the odd thought to add here and there. I have a background in writing (Columns, Features &amp;#38; Reviews) for MacUser UK, and MacWorld UK, but I'm no longer a company man, and work by myself as a small consultancy... just a thought.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi, not sure if you&#8217;re in the market for a hasbeen Brit? I&#8217;ve been reading your stuff for a few weeks now, and nodding my head in agreement/laughing my coffee up the wall at inappropriate places - and I think you have caught the zeitgeist - for css, ror, ajax etc. I might have the odd thought to add here and there. I have a background in writing (Columns, Features &amp; Reviews) for MacUser UK, and MacWorld UK, but I&#8217;m no longer a company man, and work by myself as a small consultancy&#8230; just a thought.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Ryan Tomayko</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/09/looking-for-contributors/#comment-191</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2005 22:48:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/09/looking-for-contributors/#comment-191</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Right on, Ted. You're in :) Go &lt;a href=&quot;http://lesscode.org/wp-register.php&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and create an account. You should get right in.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Right on, Ted. You&#8217;re in :) Go <a href="http://lesscode.org/wp-register.php">here</a> and create an account. You should get right in.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Ted Dziuba</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/09/looking-for-contributors/#comment-190</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2005 21:50:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/09/looking-for-contributors/#comment-190</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;My name is Ted, I'm a student from upstate NY.  I like the seemingly loose philsophical premise of this site, and am interested in perhaps becoming a contributor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To give you some idea of my background, I'm a third year undergraduate studying mathematics, and I'm currently an intern at Google, in the intranet engineering group.  I've been working with web technologies for 5 years, and have delved into such things as Python, AJAX, PHP and MySQL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven't blogged extensively, but I think I'm a good writer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>My name is Ted, I&#8217;m a student from upstate NY.  I like the seemingly loose philsophical premise of this site, and am interested in perhaps becoming a contributor.</p>
<p>To give you some idea of my background, I&#8217;m a third year undergraduate studying mathematics, and I&#8217;m currently an intern at Google, in the intranet engineering group.  I&#8217;ve been working with web technologies for 5 years, and have delved into such things as Python, AJAX, PHP and MySQL.</p>
<p>I haven&#8217;t blogged extensively, but I think I&#8217;m a good writer.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
</channel>
</rss>

<!-- Dynamic Page Served (once) in 0.321 seconds -->
<!-- Cached page served by WP-Cache -->
