<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!-- generator="wordpress/2.0.1" -->
<rss version="2.0" 
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
<channel>
	<title>Comments on: Giant solution in search of a problem</title>
	<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/15/giant-solution-in-search-of-a-problem/</link>
	<description>AAaaaaahhhhrrrrrrr!</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2007 09:12:46 +0000</pubDate>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=2.0.1</generator>

	<item>
		<title>by: alexbunardzic</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/15/giant-solution-in-search-of-a-problem/#comment-213</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2005 22:29:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/15/giant-solution-in-search-of-a-problem/#comment-213</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Jan Wikholm wrote:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;I do hope that RoR doesn’t get injected with Bloatus Maximus over the course of ten years.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hey, I'd be willing to bet large sums of money that it will get injected, big time:-) Such is the nature of the enginedering porftion of the human mind -- complicating the existing solutions is an irresistible lure. In other words, we excell at making things exorbitantly expensive. Hardly anyone is impressed with a bargain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I'm not too worried about it. Some other 'simplifier', that is, a clear thinking mind, will come along and rescue us from the future Bloatus Maximus mess, like the creator of RoR did last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember the XML initiative? It started as a small-footprint, agile little system to avoid the bloat of entrenched mainframe and other technology-driven document formats. Look at it today -- much more bloated than any mainframe format of the past ever was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pretty soon we'll need a meta-markup language to simplify the existing markup languages:-) Engineers are certainly extremely lousy when it comes to keeping things simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alex&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Jan Wikholm wrote:</p>
<p>&#8220;I do hope that RoR doesn’t get injected with Bloatus Maximus over the course of ten years.&#8221;</p>
<p>Hey, I&#8217;d be willing to bet large sums of money that it will get injected, big time:-) Such is the nature of the enginedering porftion of the human mind &#8212; complicating the existing solutions is an irresistible lure. In other words, we excell at making things exorbitantly expensive. Hardly anyone is impressed with a bargain.</p>
<p>But I&#8217;m not too worried about it. Some other &#8217;simplifier&#8217;, that is, a clear thinking mind, will come along and rescue us from the future Bloatus Maximus mess, like the creator of RoR did last year.</p>
<p>Remember the XML initiative? It started as a small-footprint, agile little system to avoid the bloat of entrenched mainframe and other technology-driven document formats. Look at it today &#8212; much more bloated than any mainframe format of the past ever was.</p>
<p>Pretty soon we&#8217;ll need a meta-markup language to simplify the existing markup languages:-) Engineers are certainly extremely lousy when it comes to keeping things simple.</p>
<p>Alex</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Jan Wikholm</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/15/giant-solution-in-search-of-a-problem/#comment-210</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2005 08:51:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/15/giant-solution-in-search-of-a-problem/#comment-210</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Very nice article. 
I do hope that RoR doesn't get injected with Bloatus Maximus over the course of ten years.
You just got yourself another subscriber to this RSS&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Very nice article.<br />
I do hope that RoR doesn&#8217;t get injected with Bloatus Maximus over the course of ten years.<br />
You just got yourself another subscriber to this RSS</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
</channel>
</rss>

<!-- Dynamic Page Served (once) in 0.251 seconds -->
<!-- Cached page served by WP-Cache -->
