<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!-- generator="wordpress/2.0.1" -->
<rss version="2.0" 
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
<channel>
	<title>Comments on: Rails / Django Chicago Debate</title>
	<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/11/17/ruby-django-meetup/</link>
	<description>AAaaaaahhhhrrrrrrr!</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2007 09:11:29 +0000</pubDate>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=2.0.1</generator>

	<item>
		<title>by: Dody Gunawinata</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/11/17/ruby-django-meetup/#comment-797</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2005 15:48:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/11/17/ruby-django-meetup/#comment-797</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;The event was interesting although it can do without the multiple 10 minutes or so delay due to projector problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were more Ruby people than Python in the room. PHP got bashed a lot in the session and there were more than enough snide comments about Java.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The attendance is about 97% white male and I can count exactly 2 female present; it started 40 minutes late and the session ended up around 6 instead of the planned 5. The choice of venue is excellent because it is easy to access from main public transport in Chicago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adrian's presentation shed light on the background of the framework and dedicate more time on the why's and culture behind the framework. There were only 4 slides of code presented, with lots of lawrence.com features being shown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David's presentation was all about code; and he showed mostly Active Records (including the latest 2 day old new features on granular handling of many to many relationships) and brush over the View and Controller part of Ruby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adrian's presentation was done with the light on because his slides were in light backround (on OO and KDE I think); David's presentation was done in dimmed light as all his slides come in black background on Windows and PowerPoint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The presentations were informative and funny. People visibly enjoyed themselves with lots of laugh during the session.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David talks more than Adrian in the QA session. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On RoR; there will be no internationalization support planned in core ROR (&quot;use plugins&quot;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The event was interesting although it can do without the multiple 10 minutes or so delay due to projector problems.</p>
<p>There were more Ruby people than Python in the room. PHP got bashed a lot in the session and there were more than enough snide comments about Java.</p>
<p>The attendance is about 97% white male and I can count exactly 2 female present; it started 40 minutes late and the session ended up around 6 instead of the planned 5. The choice of venue is excellent because it is easy to access from main public transport in Chicago.</p>
<p>Adrian&#8217;s presentation shed light on the background of the framework and dedicate more time on the why&#8217;s and culture behind the framework. There were only 4 slides of code presented, with lots of lawrence.com features being shown.</p>
<p>David&#8217;s presentation was all about code; and he showed mostly Active Records (including the latest 2 day old new features on granular handling of many to many relationships) and brush over the View and Controller part of Ruby.</p>
<p>Adrian&#8217;s presentation was done with the light on because his slides were in light backround (on OO and KDE I think); David&#8217;s presentation was done in dimmed light as all his slides come in black background on Windows and PowerPoint.</p>
<p>The presentations were informative and funny. People visibly enjoyed themselves with lots of laugh during the session.</p>
<p>David talks more than Adrian in the QA session. </p>
<p>On RoR; there will be no internationalization support planned in core ROR (&#8221;use plugins&#8221;)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Jacob Kaplan-Moss</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/11/17/ruby-django-meetup/#comment-764</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2005 23:05:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/11/17/ruby-django-meetup/#comment-764</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Ryan, I will indeed be bringing cameras (two of 'em) and unless something goes seriously wrong I'll have audio and video up within a few days of the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should come anyway, though!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ryan, I will indeed be bringing cameras (two of &#8216;em) and unless something goes seriously wrong I&#8217;ll have audio and video up within a few days of the event.</p>
<p>You should come anyway, though!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: curthibbs</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/11/17/ruby-django-meetup/#comment-762</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2005 17:33:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/11/17/ruby-django-meetup/#comment-762</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Damn... I wish I could be there!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Damn&#8230; I wish I could be there!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Ryan Tomayko</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/11/17/ruby-django-meetup/#comment-761</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2005 02:46:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/11/17/ruby-django-meetup/#comment-761</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Adrian: Perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn't realize the event was open. I'm going to try really hard to make it up there myself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Adrian: Perfect.</p>
<p>I didn&#8217;t realize the event was open. I&#8217;m going to try really hard to make it up there myself.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Adrian Holovaty</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/11/17/ruby-django-meetup/#comment-760</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2005 02:12:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/11/17/ruby-django-meetup/#comment-760</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Fellow Django developer Jacob Kaplan-Moss is planning to bring a couple of digital video cameras to the event, so, knock on wood, we'll have some video to Web-post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Fellow Django developer Jacob Kaplan-Moss is planning to bring a couple of digital video cameras to the event, so, knock on wood, we&#8217;ll have some video to Web-post.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Ryan Tomayko</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/11/17/ruby-django-meetup/#comment-758</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2005 00:36:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/11/17/ruby-django-meetup/#comment-758</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;I'm not hoping for a brawl - I think the concept is a great one. That being said, both the Python and Ruby communities are filled to the brim with smart people who like their languages and have little reservation about calling out the perceived deficiencies of others. I just think it's bound to be... lively. :) Will there be throwing of pies? Or maybe challenges that result in throwing of pies in a years time? Seems likely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Putting David and Adrian in the same room with some of the ChiPy regulars (Ian Bicking, for example) and the other smart folks around Chicago is just a great idea. It's like an all-star event for the underground. :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m not hoping for a brawl - I think the concept is a great one. That being said, both the Python and Ruby communities are filled to the brim with smart people who like their languages and have little reservation about calling out the perceived deficiencies of others. I just think it&#8217;s bound to be&#8230; lively. :) Will there be throwing of pies? Or maybe challenges that result in throwing of pies in a years time? Seems likely.</p>
<p>Putting David and Adrian in the same room with some of the ChiPy regulars (Ian Bicking, for example) and the other smart folks around Chicago is just a great idea. It&#8217;s like an all-star event for the underground. :)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Chris McAvoy</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/11/17/ruby-django-meetup/#comment-757</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2005 22:02:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/11/17/ruby-django-meetup/#comment-757</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;It's an open event.  Keep your eyes on the snakesandrubies.com site for details.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s an open event.  Keep your eyes on the snakesandrubies.com site for details.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Robb Irrgang</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/11/17/ruby-django-meetup/#comment-756</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2005 20:45:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/11/17/ruby-django-meetup/#comment-756</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Is there any information on this event and how to attend, or is this a closed event?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Is there any information on this event and how to attend, or is this a closed event?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Chris McAvoy</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/11/17/ruby-django-meetup/#comment-755</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2005 20:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/11/17/ruby-django-meetup/#comment-755</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;I sense sarcasm...hand-holding, eh?  You'd rather have a bare knuckles brawl?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I sense sarcasm&#8230;hand-holding, eh?  You&#8217;d rather have a bare knuckles brawl?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
</channel>
</rss>

<!-- Dynamic Page Served (once) in 0.384 seconds -->
<!-- Cached page served by WP-Cache -->
