<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!-- generator="wordpress/2.0.1" -->
<rss version="2.0" 
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
<channel>
	<title>Comments on: How to Miss OSCON</title>
	<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/03/how-to-miss-oscon/</link>
	<description>AAaaaaahhhhrrrrrrr!</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2007 09:54:55 +0000</pubDate>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=2.0.1</generator>

	<item>
		<title>by: Keith Veleba</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/03/how-to-miss-oscon/#comment-156</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2005 11:53:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/03/how-to-miss-oscon/#comment-156</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Ryan: Breakers in the park? I bet that cost a pretty penny.  Wi-fi?  If CP came out with that, it'd probably be charged by the minute or the byte, knowing them. Sandusky is the armpit of Northern Ohio when it comes to technology.  That's why I drive to Solon everyday to work, because there are no tech jobs in the area. It's all touristy and vacationy stuff that's seasonal and pays very little.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for viewing various stages of undress, just walk the park and look around.  It's almost a crime these days. Not that I'm complaining, of course.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ryan: Breakers in the park? I bet that cost a pretty penny.  Wi-fi?  If CP came out with that, it&#8217;d probably be charged by the minute or the byte, knowing them. Sandusky is the armpit of Northern Ohio when it comes to technology.  That&#8217;s why I drive to Solon everyday to work, because there are no tech jobs in the area. It&#8217;s all touristy and vacationy stuff that&#8217;s seasonal and pays very little.</p>
<p>As for viewing various stages of undress, just walk the park and look around.  It&#8217;s almost a crime these days. Not that I&#8217;m complaining, of course.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Ryan Tomayko</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/03/how-to-miss-oscon/#comment-155</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2005 05:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/03/how-to-miss-oscon/#comment-155</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Keith: it's too pricey for the far-east (Cleveland) tourists, too :) And tell those guys to get some wifi crankin' on the island (or peninsula or whatever). I stayed at Breakers in the park - it was nice (&lt;em&gt;gouge&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;gouge&lt;/em&gt;) but I much prefer viewing people in various stages of undress on mine own high-res laptop as opposed to their limited cable lineup. :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Keith: it&#8217;s too pricey for the far-east (Cleveland) tourists, too :) And tell those guys to get some wifi crankin&#8217; on the island (or peninsula or whatever). I stayed at Breakers in the park - it was nice (<em>gouge</em>, <em>gouge</em>) but I much prefer viewing people in various stages of undress on mine own high-res laptop as opposed to their limited cable lineup. :)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Douglas Clifton</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/03/how-to-miss-oscon/#comment-154</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2005 04:51:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/03/how-to-miss-oscon/#comment-154</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Oh man, stop picking my brain--I'm kicking myself for missing OSCON too, and I've ridden that roller coaster several times! Actually, the Raptor is my favorite.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Oh man, stop picking my brain&#8211;I&#8217;m kicking myself for missing OSCON too, and I&#8217;ve ridden that roller coaster several times! Actually, the Raptor is my favorite.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Keith Veleba</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/03/how-to-miss-oscon/#comment-153</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2005 01:55:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/03/how-to-miss-oscon/#comment-153</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;I enjoy reading your blog; glad to hear you had fun in Sandusky. I've been a native all my life and have been to CP way too many times to count.  Still a cool place, even if it's viewed as way too pricey for us locals.  My 2 year old likes Soak City a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I enjoy reading your blog; glad to hear you had fun in Sandusky. I&#8217;ve been a native all my life and have been to CP way too many times to count.  Still a cool place, even if it&#8217;s viewed as way too pricey for us locals.  My 2 year old likes Soak City a lot.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: David O'Hara</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/03/how-to-miss-oscon/#comment-152</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2005 22:07:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/03/how-to-miss-oscon/#comment-152</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;I remember when I was still in High School and the Magnum first opened, we thought it was the baddest thing ever and could wait to sneak away to try it out. Guess Cedar Point is still the bomb when it comes to the best rollercoaster in the the country...&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I remember when I was still in High School and the Magnum first opened, we thought it was the baddest thing ever and could wait to sneak away to try it out. Guess Cedar Point is still the bomb when it comes to the best rollercoaster in the the country&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Ludo&#124;Blog &#187; Echi da OSCON</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/03/how-to-miss-oscon/#comment-151</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2005 21:10:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/03/how-to-miss-oscon/#comment-151</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;[...] Difficile per noi italiani frequentare le conferenze oltreoceano, anche quelle importanti come la O'Reilly Open Source Convention che si sta tenendo in questi giorni. Ci tocca quindi rimediare con i resoconti di chi c'era, come Matt Raible segnalato dal sempre più affidabile lesscode. [...]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[&#8230;] Difficile per noi italiani frequentare le conferenze oltreoceano, anche quelle importanti come la O&#8217;Reilly Open Source Convention che si sta tenendo in questi giorni. Ci tocca quindi rimediare con i resoconti di chi c&#8217;era, come Matt Raible segnalato dal sempre più affidabile lesscode. [&#8230;]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
</channel>
</rss>

<!-- Dynamic Page Served (once) in 0.288 seconds -->
