<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!-- generator="wordpress/2.0.1" -->
<rss version="2.0" 
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
<channel>
	<title>Comments on: Welcome to lesscode.org</title>
	<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/07/07/welcome/</link>
	<description>AAaaaaahhhhrrrrrrr!</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2007 07:45:31 +0000</pubDate>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=2.0.1</generator>

	<item>
		<title>by: Thomas Joad</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/07/07/welcome/#comment-28</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2005 20:26:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/07/07/welcome/#comment-28</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Also, if you don’t like the “mandated layout” of Python, then check out Ruby. Both Python and Ruby off many of the same benefits, yet still have their distinct philosophical differences.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh yes, Ruby is great.  Indeed, Ruby is a good example of &quot;succint&quot; versus &quot;terse&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><i>Also, if you don’t like the “mandated layout” of Python, then check out Ruby. Both Python and Ruby off many of the same benefits, yet still have their distinct philosophical differences.</i></p>
<p>Oh yes, Ruby is great.  Indeed, Ruby is a good example of &#8220;succint&#8221; versus &#8220;terse&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Ryan Tomayko</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/07/07/welcome/#comment-27</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2005 18:23:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/07/07/welcome/#comment-27</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Hi Thomas,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;lesscode&quot; isn't so much a literal concept as it is an overall feeling you have when developing applications using simple tools and agile/dynamic languages. It's less everything, really; less framework, less complexity, fewer abstract concepts, etc. It's hard to put a finger on one specific aspect of the system, and we're still figuring out what works best. But there are many with strong J2EE and other &quot;enterprise&quot; backgrounds who, upon developing a front to back application using dynamic languages such as Ruby, Python, or even PHP, realize that there's something special there. That many of our assumptions about what was required to build  applications were perhaps all wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We're finding that not only can we build applications faster and with fewer lines of code but that we feel better about managing and maintaining them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi Thomas,</p>
<p>&#8220;lesscode&#8221; isn&#8217;t so much a literal concept as it is an overall feeling you have when developing applications using simple tools and agile/dynamic languages. It&#8217;s less everything, really; less framework, less complexity, fewer abstract concepts, etc. It&#8217;s hard to put a finger on one specific aspect of the system, and we&#8217;re still figuring out what works best. But there are many with strong J2EE and other &#8220;enterprise&#8221; backgrounds who, upon developing a front to back application using dynamic languages such as Ruby, Python, or even PHP, realize that there&#8217;s something special there. That many of our assumptions about what was required to build  applications were perhaps all wrong.</p>
<p>We&#8217;re finding that not only can we build applications faster and with fewer lines of code but that we feel better about managing and maintaining them.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Curt Hibbs</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/07/07/welcome/#comment-26</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2005 15:57:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/07/07/welcome/#comment-26</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Thomas: It's true, you can write unreadable code is any language -- its just easier to do in some languages. But your point is well taken and I think the idea is defintely less code that is concise, yet succinct and understandable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, if you don't like the &quot;mandated layout&quot; of Python, then check out Ruby. Both Python and Ruby off many of the same benefits, yet still have their distinct philosophical differences.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thomas: It&#8217;s true, you can write unreadable code is any language &#8212; its just easier to do in some languages. But your point is well taken and I think the idea is defintely less code that is concise, yet succinct and understandable.</p>
<p>Also, if you don&#8217;t like the &#8220;mandated layout&#8221; of Python, then check out Ruby. Both Python and Ruby off many of the same benefits, yet still have their distinct philosophical differences.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Thomas Joad</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/07/07/welcome/#comment-17</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2005 22:08:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/07/07/welcome/#comment-17</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;It would help to have clear definitions of &quot;less&quot; and &quot;code&quot;.  I've seen all sorts of Perl that did an awful lot with very few characters, but I'd be hard pressed to ever advocate that sort of coding practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, Python relieves one of having to type the closing block 'end', but at the cost of a mandated code layout.  While this is peachy keen for many,  I find that waht you gain is far less than the epressive fredom lost.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It would help to have clear definitions of &#8220;less&#8221; and &#8220;code&#8221;.  I&#8217;ve seen all sorts of Perl that did an awful lot with very few characters, but I&#8217;d be hard pressed to ever advocate that sort of coding practice.</p>
<p>Similarly, Python relieves one of having to type the closing block &#8216;end&#8217;, but at the cost of a mandated code layout.  While this is peachy keen for many,  I find that waht you gain is far less than the epressive fredom lost.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Peter Williams&#8217; Weblog &#187; Blog Archive &#187; lesscode.org</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/07/07/welcome/#comment-16</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2005 16:34:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/07/07/welcome/#comment-16</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;[...] Ryan Tomayko is trying to start a &amp;#8220;less code movement&amp;#8220;.  We’re assembling a stack of tools and techniques that are demonstrably superior and yet somehow much simpler than those of the mainstream past. [...]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[&#8230;] Ryan Tomayko is trying to start a &#8220;less code movement&#8220;.  We’re assembling a stack of tools and techniques that are demonstrably superior and yet somehow much simpler than those of the mainstream past. [&#8230;]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: David O'Hara</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/07/07/welcome/#comment-15</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2005 14:54:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/07/07/welcome/#comment-15</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;I like the site - clean and well designed. I've been reading some of the links in your &quot;About&quot; and am quite curious about your ideas and philosophies on design. Hopefully, there will be some forthcoming posts on them. &lt;em&gt;hint&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;hint&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I like the site - clean and well designed. I&#8217;ve been reading some of the links in your &#8220;About&#8221; and am quite curious about your ideas and philosophies on design. Hopefully, there will be some forthcoming posts on them. <em>hint</em> <em>hint</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Ryan Tomayko</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/07/07/welcome/#comment-14</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2005 14:41:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/07/07/welcome/#comment-14</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Here I thought I was being trendy and cool. But, yea, the novelty has worn off a bit. Better?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Here I thought I was being trendy and cool. But, yea, the novelty has worn off a bit. Better?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Jarek Zgoda</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/07/07/welcome/#comment-11</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2005 07:40:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/07/07/welcome/#comment-11</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;May I ask you to remove this orange flicking when hovering a mouse over masthead of pages? I think it will be hm... less iritating?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>May I ask you to remove this orange flicking when hovering a mouse over masthead of pages? I think it will be hm&#8230; less iritating?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
</channel>
</rss>

<!-- Dynamic Page Served (once) in 0.346 seconds -->
<!-- Cached page served by WP-Cache -->
