<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!-- generator="wordpress/2.0.1" -->
<rss version="2.0" 
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
<channel>
	<title>Comments on: Web Thinking (with bonus Feynman quotes)</title>
	<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/07/25/web-thinking/</link>
	<description>AAaaaaahhhhrrrrrrr!</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2007 09:54:25 +0000</pubDate>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=2.0.1</generator>

	<item>
		<title>by: Mike Watkins</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/07/25/web-thinking/#comment-737</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2005 08:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/07/25/web-thinking/#comment-737</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;To be fair, there are still some older folks kicking about the industry who remember simplicity... if you go back 20 years, there were less-code type solutions back then - simple message passing, files, straightforward data structures, because in some cases that's all we had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The web made simple &lt;strong&gt;ubiquitous&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;potentially homogenous&lt;/strong&gt;, and then, unsurprisingly, vendors (all the people Bosworth worked for) have been working hard to make it more complicated than it needs to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can see why some shops will resist change, in part it will be as a result of some of the real pain and horror storys out there. I've seen some pretty big projects go off the rails thanks to Microsoftitecture, or, perhaps more fairly put, theme-of-the-day architecture. On one very large product development I'm aware of, Microserfs pushed an agenda and the older, experienced, sane folks hesitated in pushing back. Hundreds of person-years of development later, they scrapped the &quot;pass everything between every object known to man as xml&quot; architecture (performance well and truly sucked) and went largely back to what they'd been doing, successfully, before.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>To be fair, there are still some older folks kicking about the industry who remember simplicity&#8230; if you go back 20 years, there were less-code type solutions back then - simple message passing, files, straightforward data structures, because in some cases that&#8217;s all we had.</p>
<p>The web made simple <strong>ubiquitous</strong> and <strong>potentially homogenous</strong>, and then, unsurprisingly, vendors (all the people Bosworth worked for) have been working hard to make it more complicated than it needs to be.</p>
<p>I can see why some shops will resist change, in part it will be as a result of some of the real pain and horror storys out there. I&#8217;ve seen some pretty big projects go off the rails thanks to Microsoftitecture, or, perhaps more fairly put, theme-of-the-day architecture. On one very large product development I&#8217;m aware of, Microserfs pushed an agenda and the older, experienced, sane folks hesitated in pushing back. Hundreds of person-years of development later, they scrapped the &#8220;pass everything between every object known to man as xml&#8221; architecture (performance well and truly sucked) and went largely back to what they&#8217;d been doing, successfully, before.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: meaningful chunks &#187; Blog Archive &#187; it conversations: adam bosworth - mysql users conference</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/07/25/web-thinking/#comment-385</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2005 20:55:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/07/25/web-thinking/#comment-385</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;[...] via web thinking (with bonus feynman quotes) [@lesscode.org] [...]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[&#8230;] via web thinking (with bonus feynman quotes) [@lesscode.org] [&#8230;]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Don&#8217;t take your memes to town [@lesscode.org]</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/07/25/web-thinking/#comment-174</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2005 15:40:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/07/25/web-thinking/#comment-174</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;[...] What&amp;#8217;s interesting in all this, is that while the toolsets and technologies are surely getting better, core Web architecture isn&amp;#8217;t changing that much. What&amp;#8217;s really happening is that people&amp;#8217;s ability to innovate is improving - that seems to come about by accepting Web thinking. In short - instead of trying to make the Web a good place for your business or technology to function, adapt your business or technology to function well on the Web. [...]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[&#8230;] What&#8217;s interesting in all this, is that while the toolsets and technologies are surely getting better, core Web architecture isn&#8217;t changing that much. What&#8217;s really happening is that people&#8217;s ability to innovate is improving - that seems to come about by accepting Web thinking. In short - instead of trying to make the Web a good place for your business or technology to function, adapt your business or technology to function well on the Web. [&#8230;]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Ludo&#124;Blog &#187; Lesscode</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/07/25/web-thinking/#comment-137</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2005 12:59:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/07/25/web-thinking/#comment-137</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;[...] L'ho consigliato su Qix qualche tempo fa ma non fa male ripeterlo qui: se vi interessa l'evoluzione prossima futura del Web e volete controbilanciare un po' i troppi post di PR o dei soliti egomaniaci, fatevi un giro su lesscode.org. Particolarmente consigliati: Web Thinking, Web Architecture Roundup, Motherhood and Apple Pie. [...]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[&#8230;] L&#8217;ho consigliato su Qix qualche tempo fa ma non fa male ripeterlo qui: se vi interessa l&#8217;evoluzione prossima futura del Web e volete controbilanciare un po&#8217; i troppi post di PR o dei soliti egomaniaci, fatevi un giro su lesscode.org. Particolarmente consigliati: Web Thinking, Web Architecture Roundup, Motherhood and Apple Pie. [&#8230;]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: iterating toward openness &#187; Blog Archive &#187; Adam Bosworth on the Future</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/07/25/web-thinking/#comment-135</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2005 22:49:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/07/25/web-thinking/#comment-135</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;[...] Lots going around late today about Adam Bosworth&amp;#8217;s closing keyonte (links to audio) at the MySQL conference. I enjoyed Ryan Tomayko&amp;#8217;s writeup most, especially this deceiving simple line: Systems that were designed through observation of the web and/or in adherence to the core principles of the web must be more suitable to the web than those that were not. This recognition will either make or break the entire open education movement, including eduCommons and the OpenCourseWares. [...]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[&#8230;] Lots going around late today about Adam Bosworth&#8217;s closing keyonte (links to audio) at the MySQL conference. I enjoyed Ryan Tomayko&#8217;s writeup most, especially this deceiving simple line: Systems that were designed through observation of the web and/or in adherence to the core principles of the web must be more suitable to the web than those that were not. This recognition will either make or break the entire open education movement, including eduCommons and the OpenCourseWares. [&#8230;]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Paul M. Jones</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/07/25/web-thinking/#comment-130</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2005 23:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/07/25/web-thinking/#comment-130</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Wow.  Exceptionally good.  I especially like the illustration during the Q&amp;#38;A at the end describing RSS1 vs RSS2 and his skepticism of top-down ontologies.  Thanks for the pointer, and for the Lesscode site.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Wow.  Exceptionally good.  I especially like the illustration during the Q&amp;A at the end describing RSS1 vs RSS2 and his skepticism of top-down ontologies.  Thanks for the pointer, and for the Lesscode site.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Jordan T. Cox</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/07/25/web-thinking/#comment-129</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2005 16:26:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/07/25/web-thinking/#comment-129</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Good audio clip.  I love itconversations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Good audio clip.  I love itconversations.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
</channel>
</rss>

<!-- Dynamic Page Served (once) in 0.303 seconds -->
