<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!-- generator="wordpress/2.0.1" -->
<rss version="2.0" 
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
<channel>
	<title>Comments on: Java Tunnel Vision</title>
	<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/28/java-tunnel-vision/</link>
	<description>AAaaaaahhhhrrrrrrr!</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2007 09:12:37 +0000</pubDate>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=2.0.1</generator>

	<item>
		<title>by: alexbunardzic</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/28/java-tunnel-vision/#comment-341</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2005 17:04:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/28/java-tunnel-vision/#comment-341</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Withheld to protect the ignorant wrote:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why are you so threatened by Java?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason I'm threatened by Java lies in the fact that I've had a misfortune to be involved in numerous Java projects that bombed. Each successive failure is giving another black eye to our profession. Many of my colleagues report same or similar experiences. Everywhere you turn, Java sems to be the touch of death. Businesses are getting very antsy after spending millions of dollars on failed Java projects. They are now desperately branching out to India, China, etc.; at least the continuation of their failed projects aren't going to cost them that much over there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don't think it's good for us, software developers, to be fostering such downward spiral movement. We need to do some damage control and stop shooting ourselves in the proverbial foot. This is why I appreciate Ryan's and others' efforts with the &lt;i&gt;lesscode&lt;/i&gt; initiative and movement. Let's work on salvaging the face of our profession. Let's work on regaining the trust we once had with the businesses. We can do it, we only need to focus some more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;You come off as a scared kid who wants revenge or something—it’s creepy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last thing I want is revenge. Revenge against whom? I was the one who worked hard on getting us here. I was the foaming-at-the-mouth Java evangelist and raving lunatic, insisting that every goddamned pattern must find its way into the product design. I'm not looking for a revenge against myself, that's for sure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for creepy, I agree -- it is creepy. I'm fighting for my survival, so it's not a pretty picture:-)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Withheld to protect the ignorant wrote:</p>
<blockquote><p>Why are you so threatened by Java?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The reason I&#8217;m threatened by Java lies in the fact that I&#8217;ve had a misfortune to be involved in numerous Java projects that bombed. Each successive failure is giving another black eye to our profession. Many of my colleagues report same or similar experiences. Everywhere you turn, Java sems to be the touch of death. Businesses are getting very antsy after spending millions of dollars on failed Java projects. They are now desperately branching out to India, China, etc.; at least the continuation of their failed projects aren&#8217;t going to cost them that much over there.</p>
<p>I don&#8217;t think it&#8217;s good for us, software developers, to be fostering such downward spiral movement. We need to do some damage control and stop shooting ourselves in the proverbial foot. This is why I appreciate Ryan&#8217;s and others&#8217; efforts with the <i>lesscode</i> initiative and movement. Let&#8217;s work on salvaging the face of our profession. Let&#8217;s work on regaining the trust we once had with the businesses. We can do it, we only need to focus some more.</p>
<blockquote><p>You come off as a scared kid who wants revenge or something—it’s creepy.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The last thing I want is revenge. Revenge against whom? I was the one who worked hard on getting us here. I was the foaming-at-the-mouth Java evangelist and raving lunatic, insisting that every goddamned pattern must find its way into the product design. I&#8217;m not looking for a revenge against myself, that&#8217;s for sure.</p>
<p>As for creepy, I agree &#8212; it is creepy. I&#8217;m fighting for my survival, so it&#8217;s not a pretty picture:-)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Assaph Mehr</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/28/java-tunnel-vision/#comment-338</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2005 02:24:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/28/java-tunnel-vision/#comment-338</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;I'm reminded how complex Java web development is whenever I train my fellow coworkers.  After I get through explaining Java, JSP, Struts, Hibernate, Ant, and an IDE, the expression is generally a very nice blank stare followed by a WTF??&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Java, with all its agile libraries, is too complex.  The only people Java seems to be drawing to its camps these days are people of India hoping to work in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m reminded how complex Java web development is whenever I train my fellow coworkers.  After I get through explaining Java, JSP, Struts, Hibernate, Ant, and an IDE, the expression is generally a very nice blank stare followed by a WTF??</p>
<p>Java, with all its agile libraries, is too complex.  The only people Java seems to be drawing to its camps these days are people of India hoping to work in the United States.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: alexbunardzic</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/28/java-tunnel-vision/#comment-333</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2005 18:48:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/28/java-tunnel-vision/#comment-333</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Stefan writes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;You seem to have ended up bitter about it while I found a way to deal with those issues and put the fun back in Java programming.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is rather fascinating, Stefan! Thanks so much for taking the trouble to elaborate on this:-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, as I've explained elsewhere, my bitterness is not about not having personal fun while doing Java, it is more related to the damage that those heavy artillery platforms are doing to our profession.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The real question (for me, at least), is: can you see your approach taking root and spilling over into the mainstream Java development? If yes, then I'd be willing to sit up and listen. If 'not really', then, much as I admire your ingenuity, I'm afraid I'd still stay wary of the overall damage that the behemoths (i.e. Java and .NET) are going to make as they continue rolling downhill.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Stefan writes:</p>
<blockquote><p>You seem to have ended up bitter about it while I found a way to deal with those issues and put the fun back in Java programming.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is rather fascinating, Stefan! Thanks so much for taking the trouble to elaborate on this:-)</p>
<p>However, as I&#8217;ve explained elsewhere, my bitterness is not about not having personal fun while doing Java, it is more related to the damage that those heavy artillery platforms are doing to our profession.</p>
<p>The real question (for me, at least), is: can you see your approach taking root and spilling over into the mainstream Java development? If yes, then I&#8217;d be willing to sit up and listen. If &#8216;not really&#8217;, then, much as I admire your ingenuity, I&#8217;m afraid I&#8217;d still stay wary of the overall damage that the behemoths (i.e. Java and .NET) are going to make as they continue rolling downhill.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: alexbunardzic</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/28/java-tunnel-vision/#comment-330</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2005 16:32:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/28/java-tunnel-vision/#comment-330</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Ryan,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;To provide value on the internet, you must piss someone off.&quot; I laughed so hard when I read this. Where did you get the quote from?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah, you're right about the sine qua non -- in general, people on the internet are the most piss-offable bunch there is. An insanely easy target, not worthy of anyone's effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I understand you being irritated with me dragging the conversation down into the mud pit. I have my reasons for doing that; allow me to briefly explain:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stefan accused me of the RoR tunnel vision; I had to retort and talk a bit more about the Java tunnel vision.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The deeper reason for doing that is that I'm starting to get alarmed by the damage Java tunnel vision is doing to our profession. What I mean by that is that, due to the stubborn (I almost want to use the word 'dogmatic') insistence on Java's infallibility, the mainstream software development community is forcing businesses to reach out for desperate measures. This is also a personal peeve of mine, because we've just lost a multi-million dollar project to a company in India. This is due to the exorbitantly expensive price tag, enforced on the project by the idiosyncrasies of the Java EE platform.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we have here is something closely resembling a panicky situation, where the business are starting to realize that they simply cannot afford to keep paying millions of dollars for every little thing they need to do. And because they have the blinders on, and believe that the only way to accomplish something in a reasonable fashion is to stick to the Java EE/.NET world, they are now scrambling and are trying two types of desperate measures (desperate times demand desperate measures):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a) Outsource overseas, where labor is more than twice cheaper
b) Invest in some code generation tool/process/gimmick&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both of the above desperate measures hurt our profession in more than one way. By insisting that Java (or its derivate, .NET) is the only sensible way to go, we as the developers community are shooting ourselves in the foot, or cutting the branch on which we all sit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need to be proactive and go out of our way to prove it to the stakeholders that there is a better, more affordable way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, we'll continue to face the prospect of working in an ever shrinking idustry. I think that would be a shame for such a nice, dynamic, beautiful type of work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ryan,</p>
<p>&#8220;To provide value on the internet, you must piss someone off.&#8221; I laughed so hard when I read this. Where did you get the quote from?</p>
<p>Yeah, you&#8217;re right about the sine qua non &#8212; in general, people on the internet are the most piss-offable bunch there is. An insanely easy target, not worthy of anyone&#8217;s effort.</p>
<p>I understand you being irritated with me dragging the conversation down into the mud pit. I have my reasons for doing that; allow me to briefly explain:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Stefan accused me of the RoR tunnel vision; I had to retort and talk a bit more about the Java tunnel vision.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The deeper reason for doing that is that I&#8217;m starting to get alarmed by the damage Java tunnel vision is doing to our profession. What I mean by that is that, due to the stubborn (I almost want to use the word &#8216;dogmatic&#8217;) insistence on Java&#8217;s infallibility, the mainstream software development community is forcing businesses to reach out for desperate measures. This is also a personal peeve of mine, because we&#8217;ve just lost a multi-million dollar project to a company in India. This is due to the exorbitantly expensive price tag, enforced on the project by the idiosyncrasies of the Java EE platform.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>What we have here is something closely resembling a panicky situation, where the business are starting to realize that they simply cannot afford to keep paying millions of dollars for every little thing they need to do. And because they have the blinders on, and believe that the only way to accomplish something in a reasonable fashion is to stick to the Java EE/.NET world, they are now scrambling and are trying two types of desperate measures (desperate times demand desperate measures):</p>
<p>a) Outsource overseas, where labor is more than twice cheaper<br />
b) Invest in some code generation tool/process/gimmick</p>
<p>Both of the above desperate measures hurt our profession in more than one way. By insisting that Java (or its derivate, .NET) is the only sensible way to go, we as the developers community are shooting ourselves in the foot, or cutting the branch on which we all sit.</p>
<p>We need to be proactive and go out of our way to prove it to the stakeholders that there is a better, more affordable way.</p>
<p>Otherwise, we&#8217;ll continue to face the prospect of working in an ever shrinking idustry. I think that would be a shame for such a nice, dynamic, beautiful type of work.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Seth Gordon</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/28/java-tunnel-vision/#comment-328</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2005 14:55:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/28/java-tunnel-vision/#comment-328</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;I think the kinds of problems J2EE (and its successor frameworks) was designed to address are problems that Java is fundamentally unsuited to solve, because of &lt;a href=&quot;http://dynamic.ropine.com/yo/tech/java/enterprise.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;the constraints of its type system&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I think the kinds of problems J2EE (and its successor frameworks) was designed to address are problems that Java is fundamentally unsuited to solve, because of <a href="http://dynamic.ropine.com/yo/tech/java/enterprise.html">the constraints of its type system</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Lorenzo Gatti</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/28/java-tunnel-vision/#comment-324</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2005 08:16:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/28/java-tunnel-vision/#comment-324</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;I don't think Visual Age for Java did much harm to the Java Platform. It was the first Java development environment I used and all later ones, including Notepad plus a console, have been more effective and efficient; but many of its worst features were an unpleasant implementation of unpleasant standards like early J2EE and many others, like the repository, were idiosyncratic and caused no lasting damage.
VAJ was a forerunner of the bloated IDEs of today, with the main difference that it had to make up for the modest inherent complexity of Java with a wealth of proprietary IBM solutions to IBM problems (e.g. interfacing with CICS software), while current tools can justify their continued existence and outrageous price with a larger J2EE platform, a lot of web services complications and if necessary with machine-readable UML and the accompanying model driven architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I don&#8217;t think Visual Age for Java did much harm to the Java Platform. It was the first Java development environment I used and all later ones, including Notepad plus a console, have been more effective and efficient; but many of its worst features were an unpleasant implementation of unpleasant standards like early J2EE and many others, like the repository, were idiosyncratic and caused no lasting damage.<br />
VAJ was a forerunner of the bloated IDEs of today, with the main difference that it had to make up for the modest inherent complexity of Java with a wealth of proprietary IBM solutions to IBM problems (e.g. interfacing with CICS software), while current tools can justify their continued existence and outrageous price with a larger J2EE platform, a lot of web services complications and if necessary with machine-readable UML and the accompanying model driven architecture.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: John</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/28/java-tunnel-vision/#comment-321</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2005 01:44:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/28/java-tunnel-vision/#comment-321</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;The main problem is not so much with the Java language, as such (it has its warts and defects, of course, but so do other languages). Nor is it the J2EE platform with all its TLAs (and XTLAs). The main problem is that somehow, Java developers think that all J2EE apps need the works; and that means EJBs and all. The majority of applications I have seen that use EJBs have no need for remoting objects. Nonetheless, the development team have been seduced by the cry of scalability. Rarely is there a cost benefit analysis to justify the added complexity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The main problem is not so much with the Java language, as such (it has its warts and defects, of course, but so do other languages). Nor is it the J2EE platform with all its TLAs (and XTLAs). The main problem is that somehow, Java developers think that all J2EE apps need the works; and that means EJBs and all. The majority of applications I have seen that use EJBs have no need for remoting objects. Nonetheless, the development team have been seduced by the cry of scalability. Rarely is there a cost benefit analysis to justify the added complexity.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Withheld to protect the ignorant</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/28/java-tunnel-vision/#comment-318</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2005 20:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/28/java-tunnel-vision/#comment-318</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;I came to lesscode after reading some of Ryan's exceptional articles.    Ryan is obviously pro-dynamic language, yet his stuff isn't nearly as prickly as yours is.  Why are you so threatened by Java?  You come off as a scared kid who wants revenge or something--it's creepy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I came to lesscode after reading some of Ryan&#8217;s exceptional articles.    Ryan is obviously pro-dynamic language, yet his stuff isn&#8217;t nearly as prickly as yours is.  Why are you so threatened by Java?  You come off as a scared kid who wants revenge or something&#8211;it&#8217;s creepy.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Stefan Arentz</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/28/java-tunnel-vision/#comment-317</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2005 17:29:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/28/java-tunnel-vision/#comment-317</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Alex, I found myself in exactly the same position as you are now. Stuck in the downward spiral of 'Sun Java Technology Complexity'. I'll explain that in more detail. In the end we just made different choices to deal with Java as a development platform. You seem to have ended up bitter about it while I found a way to deal with those issues and put the fun back in Java programming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sateh.com/blog/2005/08/java_tunnel_vision.php&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://www.sateh.com/blog/2005/08/java_tunnel_vision.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Alex, I found myself in exactly the same position as you are now. Stuck in the downward spiral of &#8216;Sun Java Technology Complexity&#8217;. I&#8217;ll explain that in more detail. In the end we just made different choices to deal with Java as a development platform. You seem to have ended up bitter about it while I found a way to deal with those issues and put the fun back in Java programming.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.sateh.com/blog/2005/08/java_tunnel_vision.php">http://www.sateh.com/blog/2005/08/java_tunnel_vision.php</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Alex Schroeder</title>
		<link>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/28/java-tunnel-vision/#comment-310</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2005 09:28:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://lesscode.org/2005/08/28/java-tunnel-vision/#comment-310</guid>
					<description>&lt;p&gt;I knew our company was going down the wrong track when we started using a Struts-like framework for a finance website and I discovered to my dismay that to be über-flexible and dynamic the code for a simple currency converter had more layers to it than we had developers in our team.  I don't remember the details, but I think to add a new field to one of the screens we had to modify or at least check a file of JSP, XML, XSL, Session Bean, Entity Bean, deployment descriptors, etc.  It was totally inappropriate.  I left the project convinced that the way we used Java was designed either by architecture astronauts or designed for teams of several dozens of software engineers.  But since all the coding I do for a living happens in teams no larger than a dozen developers including the project manager, I suspect that we're using the wrong tools.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I knew our company was going down the wrong track when we started using a Struts-like framework for a finance website and I discovered to my dismay that to be über-flexible and dynamic the code for a simple currency converter had more layers to it than we had developers in our team.  I don&#8217;t remember the details, but I think to add a new field to one of the screens we had to modify or at least check a file of JSP, XML, XSL, Session Bean, Entity Bean, deployment descriptors, etc.  It was totally inappropriate.  I left the project convinced that the way we used Java was designed either by architecture astronauts or designed for teams of several dozens of software engineers.  But since all the coding I do for a living happens in teams no larger than a dozen developers including the project manager, I suspect that we&#8217;re using the wrong tools.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
</channel>
</rss>

<!-- Dynamic Page Served (once) in 0.609 seconds -->
<!-- Cached page served by WP-Cache -->
